A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 4, Accession 4 FA1186
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Programs, Projects, and Proposals, 8
  - Project on Asian Studies in Education (PASE) - Reports and Proposals, 1971-1975 (Box 28, Folder 267)
  - Project on Asian Studies in Education (PASE) - Forms of Union, Workshop on Japan, 1974 February 22-23 (Box 28, Folder 268)
  - Educational Programs - General, 1971-1976 (Box 28, Folder 269-270)
  - Educational Programs - Letters from Teachers, 1971-1975 (Box 28, Folder 271)
  - Educational Programs - Service Center for Teachers of Asian Studies (Ohio State University), 1971-1975 (Box 28, Folder 272)
  - Educational Programs - Boston Project (World Affairs Council of Boston, Teachers' Information Center), 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 273)
  - Educational Programs - Harvard University (Sarah Benet, Ezra Vogel), 1972-1974 (Box 28, Folder 274)
  - Educational Programs - C.H.I.N.A. Project (Colorado Women's College), 1971-1973 (Box 29, Folder 275)
    Chinese Humanities: An Inquiry into New Approaches.
  - Educational Programs - American Society for Eastern Arts, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 276)
  - Educational Programs - Center for War-Peace Studies, 1972-1974 (Box 29, Folder 277-278)
  - Secondary Education - General, 1971-1976 (Box 29, Folder 279)
  - Secondary Education - Conference Reports, 1970-1975 (Box 29, Folder 280)
  - Secondary Education - School Conferences, 1970-1974 (Box 29, Folder 281)
  - Princeton-in-Asia (Robert Atmore), 1971-1974 (Box 29, Folder 282)
    Teachers conference, 1973.
  - Directory of Asian Studies in Secondary Education (Manuscript), 1971 (Box 29, Folder 283)
- Ping Pong Diplomacy, 9
  The Ping Pong Diplomacy files document the Chinese Table Tennis Team's historic visit to the U.S. in April 1972. The U.S. team had visited China in 1971. Traveling only a few weeks after President Nixon's trip to China, the Chinese Table Tennis Team was the first delegation to visit the U. S. from the People's Republic of China.
  Records concern arrangements and planning for the visit, fundraising, press coverage, and follow-up. In 1997 participants held a twenty-fifth anniversary reunion.
  - Ping Pong Diplomacy - General, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 284)
    General Correspondence; Threatening Letter; History of Table Tennis; Table Tennis Visit Center.
  - American Table Tennis Delegation to China, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 285)
    Illustrated booklet, published in Chinese.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation (Namelists), 1972 (Box 30, Folder 286)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Planning and Background (Instruction and Guide - PRC Visit), 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 287)
    Also includes early planning correspondence.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - U. S. Table Tennis Association, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 288)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Operations Team, Memos and Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 289)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - U. S. Table Tennis Association (USTTA) - NCUSCR Joint Committee - Mailings, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 290)
    Joint Committee of the United States Table Tennis Association and the NCUSCR formed to coordinate the the Chinese Table Tennis team's U. S, visit.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - U. S. Table Tennis Association (USTTA) - NCUSCR Joint Committee - Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 291)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Budget, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 292)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Interpreters, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 293)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Itineraries, 1972 April 12-30 (Box 30, Folder 294)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Invitations from Cities and States, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 295)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Invitations from Schools, Colleges, and Local Table Tennis Clubs, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 296)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Possible Participatory Agencies, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 297)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Travel Planning and Site Bids, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 298)
    Includes correspondence with American Express Company and Pan Am World Airways.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Local Host Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 299)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Visits and Local Itineraries, 1972 April 12-30 (Box 31, Folder 300-301)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Commemorative Booklet, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 302)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Commemorative Gifts and Flags, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 303)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Books Presented to the Chinese Delegation, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 304)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - General, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 305)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - General, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 306)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Planning (William T. Gossett), 1971 (Box 32, Folder 307)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Media Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 308)
    Includes press credentials.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 309)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries - Table Tennis, USA vs. China (Wide World of Sports), 1972 April 15; DVD (Box 32, Folder 309)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
    One of two DVDs with same title - presumably duplicates.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries - Table Tennis, USA vs. China (Wide World of Sports), 1972 April 15; DVD (Box 32, Folder 309)
    One of two DVDs with the same title - presumably duplicates.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries - Chinese Ping Pong Footage (in English), 1972 April; DVD (Box 32, Folder 309)
    One hour. One of two DVDs, presumably duplicates.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries - Chinese Ping Pong Footage (in English), 1972 April; DVD (Box 32, Folder 309)
    One hour. One of two DVDs with the same title, presumably duplicates.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries - Chinese Ping Pong Footage (in Chinese), 1972 April; DVD (Box 32, Folder 309)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction
    30 minutes. One of two DVDs with the same title, presumably duplicates. Title written on disc: Chinese Ping Pong Team in the U.S.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Public Relations - Documentaries - Chinese Ping Pong Footage (in Chinese), 1972 April; DVD (Box 32, Folder 309)
    30 minutes. One of two DVDs with the same title, presumably duplicates.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Press Coverage - General (Clippings), 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 310)
    Includes Souvenir Issues of Table Tennis Topics, 39:1 (1971 May-June), and 40:1 (1972 May-June; incomplete) (published by the U. S. Table Tennis Association).
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Press Coverage - General (Clippings), 1971-1972; FA1186:040 (Box 62)
    Souvenir Issues of Table Tennis Topics, 39:1 (1971 May-June), and 40:1 (1972 May-June; incomplete) (published by the U. S. Table Tennis Association). Oversized: Table Tennis Topics (1971 and 1972 May- June issues)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Press Coverage and Publicity - Detroit (Clippings), 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 311)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Publicity - New York City, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 312)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - General, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 313)
    Correspondence and IRS ruling
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - Requests for Contributions, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 314)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - Declinations, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 315-316)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - List of Contributors and Host Committees for Table Tennis Delegation, 1972 December (Box 33, Folder 317)
    Information provided to the Ambassador of the PRC to the United Nations.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - Post-Visit Appeals, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 318)
    Fundraising appeals to cover deficit owing from Table Tennis Delegation's visit.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - Marcia Goldstein Letters, 1972 February-April (Box 33, Folder 319)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Fundraising - Fund for Peace Contributors List, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 320)
    Contributions under 25 dollars - not sent.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Table Tennis - Lists for Thank Yous and Acknowledgment, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 321-322)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Thank Yous from Carl Stover, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 323-324)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Thank Yous and Responses, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 325)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Ping Pong Diplomacy - A View from Behind the Scenes (Eckstein), 1990, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 326)
    Paper by Ruth Eckstein.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Ping Pong Diplomacy Revisited (Cunningham), 2011 (Box 34, Folder 327)
    Paper by William J. Cunningham.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 328)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Planning Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 34, Folder 329)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Correspondence with Invitees, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 330)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Contact Information, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 331)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Invitations and Responses, 1997 July 24 (Box 34, Folder 332)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Event Planning and Arrangements, 1997 July 24 (Box 34, Folder 333)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Media Coverage, 1997 July 24 (Box 34, Folder 334)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Media Coverage, 1997 July 24; FA1186:016 (Box 61)
    5 black and white images of participants. Includes Chinese and American team members, Tricia Nixon.
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation Visit - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Celebration - Follow Up, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 335)
- Development, 10
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Cities (General), 1967-1968 (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - New York, 1967-1968 (Box 23, Folder 208)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Santa Barbara, 1966-1968 (Box 23, Folder 209)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Washington, DC, 1967-1968 (Box 23, Folder 210)
    Washington Contacts of Political Assistance to the National Committee.
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Washington, DC, Lawyers, 1967-1968 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Washington, DC, Representative - John E. Merriam, Policy Management Systems, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Ching, Peter P. S., 1966-1969 (Box 23, Folder 213)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Council on Religion and International Affairs (CRIA), 1968 (Box 23, Folder 214)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Labor Leaders, 1966-1970 (Box 23, Folder 215)
  - Community Leaders (Contacts) - Tang Ping Yuan, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 216)